JAMIE HOLMES

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING LEADERSHIP

CONTACT

- 077381 06784
- **Q** London, UK
- www.websitelink.com

EDUCATION

BA Econ & Computer Science

University of Durham First Class Hons | 2013

SKILLS

- Developing People
- Hiring Great Engineers
- Distributed Systems Design
- Agile Principles
- DevOps
- Customer Focus
- Security First Mindset
- Stakeholder Management

INTERESTS

Reading, Chess, Travel, Golfing, Skiing, Hiking

PROFILE

Experienced leader of large software engineering teams spread across multiple locations. Responsible for guiding teams through the development and support of business critical applications at a scale of tens of millions of users. I combine my past deep technical experience with customer obsession and a passion for developing people to create highly effective and sustainable teams.

EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

TESCO | LONDON | 2020 - PRESENT

Responsible for the strategic leadership and management of the wider Identity engineering team, comprising circa 50 engineers in three locations. Collectively accountable for development and support of 40 production microservices, which scale to ~20,000 TPS at peak.

- Setting high level technical objectives, working with product leadership to define roadmap.
- Creating engineering practices to rapidly deliver high quality and scalable software.
- Putting in place structures and processes to continually develop our people.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

TESCO | WELWYN GARDEN CITY | 2019 - 2020

I lead teams of software engineers to create highly performant, scalable and resilient solutions for identity management at Tesco.

We use a range of modern technologies, including Java (Spring Boot, Webflux, Vertx, Kafka, Kotlin, Cassandra), .Net (SQL Server), Docker, Kubernetes, Splunk and many others.

I also lead our technology Graduate and Intern programmes, having responsibility for recruiting, developing and supporting around 30 early careers colleagues each year.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

TESCO | WELWYN GARDEN CITY | 2013 - 2019

Various software engineering roles across a number of domains. Developed and supported production applications on the JDK and .NET stacks. Promoted over the years from Associate Software Engineer to Senior Software Engineer, with responsibility for system design and driving architectural processes.